lawyer.com 2018-06-30

# Lawyer.com Privacy Policy

Lawyer.com INC. ("Company") manages the Lawyer.com website ("Website") and provides this Privacy Policy because we value your right to privacy.

This Policy is effective as of December 22, 2009 and governs the collection of personal information through our Website on or after this date. This Policy describes the types of information we may collect from visitors and how that information is used.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully before providing us with any personal information. If you have any questions or concerns about this Policy, please know that we will handle your requests with care. You may Contact Us at any time to discuss this Privacy Policy.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM UNREGISTERED USERS

Unregistered Users are users that visit our Website and have not signed up for an account at our Website for the purpose of using one or more of our services or have not engaged in services at our Website where the user has provided us with personal information. The information we collect from unregistered users is limited. We log your IP address in order to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Website, and to track usage statistics. Your IP address may vary each time you visit, or it may stay the same. We may log other non-personal information such as the type of internet browser that you use or your connection speed. It would be extremely difficult for us to identify you through your IP address, browser type, or other non-personal information that we collect and we make no attempt to do so.

If you reached our Website by clicking on a link or advertisement on another website, we may log that information as well. We may place a small "cookie" file on your computer's hard drive. A cookie may contain information that allows us to track your path through our Website and to determine whether you have visited us before. You may elect not to accept cookies by changing settings in your browser; however, by not accepting cookies some or all of the functions of our Website may not work for you.

Unless you register with us, cookies we place on your computer will not contain personally identifiable information. We may use cookies to help us understand how visitors use our Website, and to help us to improve our Website. We also compile this information and use it in the aggregate to determine common themes among our visitors or trends which we can use to improve the service to our users.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM REGISTERED USERS

Registered Users are users that sign up for an account at our Website for the purpose of using one or more of our services or that use our services and in doing so provide us with personal information. You can register at our Website to take advantage of personalization features as well as services that we offer. If you choose to register with us, it may allow you access to unique features of our Website. For example, you may enhance you lawyer or law firm profile, post or respond to legal questions, download legal forms, and other services. By registering you can receive notification of new services or changes in services that we offer.

If you register with us, we will collect personal information from you that you enter into our forms in addition to the non-personal information described above that we collect from unregistered users. Such personal information will include information about you or about other profiles that you manage on behalf of other lawyers and will include information such as name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, practice specialties, and other information about you and/or your law firm, username and password, and contact information. The information we collect may vary. We may store all or some of this information such as your login user name in a cookie file on your hard drive so that our system will recognize you each time you visit our Website. In that way, we can save your preferences between visits and present you with a customized Website each time you visit.

If you enter credit card information into our secure payment page we will use a secure connection to retrieve this information and pass it on to our authorized secure payment processor. We do not store your credit card number unless you provide your billing information to us outside of our secure payment page. We do provide you with information on the name of the payment processor prior to you providing us with payment information.

If you reach our Website through one of our partners and you choose to register with us, we may be required to give our partner your registration information.

To improve services and enhance personalization, we may periodically obtain information about you from other independent third-party sources and add it to your registration information. You always have the ability to remove any information about yourself on our Website.

Additionally, authorized personnel may update your registration information to accurately reflect any new information included in communications received from you.

## HOW WE USE THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

As a directory site you recognize that one benefit of you providing us with personal information is that we make it easier for Internet searches to see this information in your profile and learn about your background, specialties and other information that you provide us. Registering allows you to personalize our Website so that it is more useful to you and to provide other visitors to our site with an enhanced profile of you or your law firm. It also allows you to log in to our Website automatically each time you visit, rather than manually typing in your username and password every time you visit, although this may not always be the case.

We may use your personal information to periodically contact you with news or important information, to provide you with other information or invitations related to your membership, and to request your feedback on our Website. In addition to these periodic updates, we may email you additional marketing materials that you have requested. These might include opt-in newsletters and partner offers. By using the Website, you consent to receive emails from Company. Any emails sent that are not Lawyer.com account and service related emails will allow you to opt out of the receipt of such emails; provided however, you may not opt out of receiving Lawyer.com account and service related emails that relate to the provision and management of your listing and service at Lawyer.com. To be removed from Lawyer.com account and service related emails you may delete your account at Lawyer.com and discontinue use of the Lawyer.com services. To delete your account please submit this request in writing via the Contact Us area.

We may also use certain information that you provide in order to present you with advertising that you may find interesting. This benefits both of us. It benefits us because advertising helps pay the bills, and we can charge our advertisers more if they know that their ads have been sufficiently targeted and this in turns allows us to offer a broader range of free or lower cost services. It benefits you because you see advertising that is more likely to be of interest to you.

## DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO OTHER PARTIES

Unless specifically stated that a piece of information will not be publically displayed, we will publically display, on your behalf, the Personal Information that you provide as part of your Lawyer and Law Firm profiles for user searches where you are a match for the search criteria.

We may share some of your personally identifiable information with our parent company and subsidiaries or with entities engaged in providing services to us where the sharing of information is needed as part of the provision of services. We also may share your information in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, and in the unlikely event of bankruptcy. We require such parties to agree to use any such personally-identifiable data solely for the purpose of providing the specified services we have requested from them or solely for the purpose of providing the services that you have requested from us. These entities or other parties must abide by the same provisions of the Privacy Policy and also comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications.

## DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IF REQUIRED BY LAW

We must cooperate with legal authorities, and may in some circumstances be required to disclose personally identifiable information in response to requests from law enforcement authorities, or in response to a subpoena or other legal process. We may turn over information about you if we believe we must in order to prevent a violation of the law.

You also consent to our disclosing information about you in the course of legal proceedings if we are legally required to do so, if we reasonably believe that doing so may mitigate our liability, or if doing so will assist us in enforcing our legal rights.

## DATA CONTROLLER AND CONTRACTING PARTIES

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the "GDPR"), the Data Controller is Lawyer.com,INC registered in the State of Delaware, United States of America with a registered address at 25 Mountainview Blvd, Suite 204 Basking Ridge, NJ 07920

You can contact our Data Protection Officer by sending an email to privacy@corp.lawyer.com or by writing to:

Lawyer.com, INC

Attn: Legal Department

25 Mountainview Blvd. Ste 204

Basking Ridge, NJ 07920 

## CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy should we deem it advisable to do so.

If we make material changes that will affect personal information we have already collected from you, we will make every reasonable effort to notify you of the changes, and to give you the opportunity to amend or cancel your registration. We take your privacy seriously; please don't hesitate to Contact Us with any questions or concerns you may have.
